Guide to the Associated Actors and Artistes of America Records WAG.110
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Associated Actors and Artistes of America Records
1909-2014
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Associated Actors and Artistes of America
Fortuno, Anne
Barry, Harriet R.
WAG.110
22.5 Linear Feet in 21 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, 1 flat box, and 1 oversize folder in shared housing
The Associated Actors and Artists of America was founded in 1919 as an umbrella organization composed of nine autonomous performing arts unions. The main purpose of the Four A's since its founding has been to represent the affiliates' common interests and to resolve jurisdictional problems. These records include the Four A's constitutions, correspondence, financial records and meeting minutes.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Associated Actors and Artistes of America via Harriet Barry (Executive Assistant), 1995. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1995.023, 1995.024, and NPA 2002.006.
Additional materials were donated by Anne Fortuno, assistant to the President of the Associated Actors and Artistes of America, in 2014. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2014.145 and 2014.162.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Associated Actors and Artistes of America (AAAA, also known as the 4A's), chartered in 1919 by the American Federation of Labor, is a New York-based umbrella organization of several autonomous unions representing different types of performing artists, including the Actors Equity Association, the American Federation of Television and Radio Artists, the American Guild of Musical Artists, the American Guild of Variety Artists, and the Screen Actors Guild.
The Four A's was founded out of a conflict between the White Rats Actors Union of America, an old variety performers' union formed in 1909, and the Actors' Equity Association of America, an organization formed in 1913 to represent performers of the legitimate stage, over the acquisition of a charter from the American Federation of Labor. The gradual demise of the White Rats as an industry force led that union to merge with Equity and a number of smaller unions by July 1919, resulting in the formation of the Associated Actors and Artistes of America.
The main purpose of the Four A's since its founding has been to represent the affiliates' common interests, and to resolve jurisdictional problems between and among them, and in regard to individual actors working a range of entertainment sectors. When ethnic and foreign language theater still flourished, the Four A's affiliated included not only Actors Equity, Chorus Equity, and the Grand Opera Choral Alliance, but also the (German) White Rats, the Hebrew Actors Unions, the Hebrew Chorus Unions of New York and Philadelphia, the Hungarian Actors and Artists Association, the Italian Actors Union, the Polish Actors Union, and the Yiddish Playwrights League.
Technological changes in performance industries gave rise to new or growing affiliates including the American Federation of Radio Artists (AFRA), the Screen Actors Guild (SAG), the Screen Extras Guild (SEG), and the Television Authority (TVA), which later merged with AFRA to become the American Federation of Radio and Television Artists (AFTRA).
The demise of variety fields and the rise of television were the major issues to between the late 1930's and the early 1970's. Variety unions have been historically weak and controversial members of the Four A's, and there were repeated allegations of internal corruption and mismanagement, reflected in the 1960's and 1970's in an investigation of AGVA by the United States Senate, and in an internal 4A's investigation. The Four A's formed a Television Committee as early as 1938, and later the Television Authority, a temporary organization made up of five affiliates: Actor's Equity, Chorus Equity, the American Guild of Musical Artists, the American Guild of Variety Artists, and the American Federation of Radio Artists. The inability of these and other unions to decide upon an acceptable merger strategy led AFRA to extend a merger invitation to the TVA in 1952 and to form a new affiliate, AFTRA.
Sources:
Thomas Colley, "A Historical Study of the White Rats of America" (Master's Thesis, Wayne State University, 1967), copy in Box 7, Folder 20.
Scope and Content Note
The collection reflects both the day-to-day operations of the Associated Actors and Artistes of America and the larger social concerns that affiliates engaged. The majority of the collection is comprised of the records of American Guild of Variety Artists (AGVA) affiliates and other affiliate groups, including several ethnicity-based affiliates. The collection also contains the Four A's constitutions, minutes, financial records, and correspondence of the presidents and other officers. There is a small amount of information on the Four A's community activities.
Arrangement
The files are arranged into 8 series:
I. Constitutions
II. Minutes
III. Correspondence
IV. Financial Records
V. Community Activities
VI. Subjects
VII. Affiliates
VIII. Unprocessed Materials
Folders are arranged alphabetically or chronologically within each series. Materials in Series VIII have not been arrangement by an archivist.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to the fragile nature of the original materials, researchers must use the microfilmed version of Series II: Minutes, Subseries II.A: Microfilm; microfilm call number is R-7420.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Minutes (administrative records); Constitutions.; Entertainers |z United States.; Entertainment industry.; Correspondence.; Labor unions |x Screenwriters |z United States.; Financial records; Collective labor agreements |x Motion picture industry |z United States.; Collective labor agreements |x Stagehands |z United States.; Performing arts |z United States |x Entertainers.; Collective labor agreements |x Entertainers |z United States.; Musicians |x Labor unions |z United States.; Collective labor agreements |x Actors |z United States.; Actors -- Labor unions -- United States.; Labor unions |x Entertainers |z United States.; Italian Actors Union; American Guild of Variety Artists; Screen Extras Guild; Screen Actors Guild; Hebrew Actors Union.; American Federation of Television and Radio Artists; O'Neal, Frederick, 1905-1992; Actors' Equity Association; American Guild of Musical Artists; Associated Actors and Artistes of America; Fortuno, Anne; Barry, Harriet R.
- Series I: Constitutions, 1916-1995
  Scope and Content Note
  Contains both original drafts and published copies.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Constitutions, 1916-1935 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Constitutions, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Constitutions, 1939, 1951, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Constitutions, 1970, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Constitutions, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Constitutions, 1990-1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series II: Minutes, 1920-1992
  Contains minutes of international board meetings and annual conventions, but it does not reflect complete records of either one. The minutes document the developement of the variety and vaudeville unions from the American Federation of Actors into the American Guild of Variety Artists, the clashing definitions by representatives of Actors Equity and the Screen Actors Guild over television performance, the Four A's involvement in AGVA's governance in the early 1970s, and other topics. Researchers must use microfilmed versions if available.
  - Subseries II:A: Microfilm
    - Minutes, 1919-1938 (Film R-7420, Reel 1)
    - Minutes, 1939 (Film R-7420, Reel 2)
      Existence and Location of Originals
      Originals in Box 12. Researchers must use microfilm.
    - Minutes, 1940-1948 (Film R-7420, Reel 3)
      Originals in Box 13. Researchers must use microfilm.
    - Minutes, 1949 (Film R-7420, Reel 4)
      Originals in Box 14. Researchers must use microfilm.
    - Minutes, 1950-1954 (Film R-7420, Reel 5)
    - Minutes, 1955-1965 (Film R-7420, Reel 6)
    - Minutes, 1966-1972 (Film R-7420, Reel 7)
      Originals in Box 15. Researchers must use microfilm.
    - Minutes, 1973-1977 (Film R-7420, Reel 8)
      Originals in Boxes 15 and 16. Researchers must use microfilm.
    - Minutes, 1978-1982 (Film R-7420, Reel 9)
      Originals in Box 16. Researchers must use microfilm.
  - Subseries II:B: Paper
    - Minutes, 1920-1937 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Minutes, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Minutes, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Minutes, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Minutes, 1944-1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Minutes, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Minutes, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Minutes, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Minutes, 1955-1960 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Minutes, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Minutes, 1966-1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Minutes, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Minutes, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Minutes, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Minutes, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Minutes, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Minutes, ca.1919-1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Minutes, ca.1992-1997 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Series III: Correspondence, 1919-1990
  Contains the correspondence of the president and other officers, and correspondents include political figures and legal counsel, the AFL and AFL-CIO, the U.S. Department of Labor, and various exchanges re the Taft-Hartley Law.
  Arranged chronologically within each name, title or topic.
  - Officers: President, 1925-1929, 1937-Apr 1938 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Officers: President, May 1938-Dec 1938 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Officers: President, Jan-Apr 1939 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Officers: President, Apr-Aug 1939 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Officers: President, Sep-Dec 1939 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Officers: President, Jan-Apr 1940 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Officers: President, May-Dec 1940 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Officers: President, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Officers: President, 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Officers: President, 1944-1947 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Officers: President, 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Officers: President, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Officers: President, 1954-1957 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Officers: President, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Officers: President, 1960-1962 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Officers: President, 1963-1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Officers: President Frank Gillmore, Personal (mostly), 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Officers: President Frank Gillmore, Personal (mostly), 1940-1943 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Officers: Exec Secretary, 1919-1925 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Officers: Exec Secretary, 1926-1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Officers: Treasurer, 1919-1921 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Officers: Treasurer, 1922-1923, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Officers: First Vice-Pres, Misc, 1925-1960 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Legal Counsel, Misc, 1937-1947 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Legal Counsel, Misc, 1953-1963 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Legislative Committee, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Legislative Committee, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Legislative/Political, 1937-1940 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Legislative/Political, 1941-1955 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Legislative/Political, 1957-1963 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Taft-Hartley Act, 1947-1950 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Taft-Hartley Act, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Taft-Hartley Act, 1953-1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - With American Federation of Labor, 1920-1925 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - With American Federation of Labor, 1926-May 1927 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - With American Federation of Labor, Jun 1927-1928 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - With American Federation of Labor, 1929-1934 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - With American Federation of Labor and CIO, 1935-1940 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - With American Federation of Labor and CIO, 1941-1948 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - With American Federation of Labor and CIO, 1949-1955 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - With AFL-CIO, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - With AFL-CIO, 1958-May 1959 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - With AFL-CIO, Jun-Dec 1959 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - With AFL-CIO, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - With AFL-CIO, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - With AFL-CIO, 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - With U.S. Departments of Labor, 1920-1930, 1938, 1944-1964 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Series IV: Financial Records, 1920-1984
  Mainly of copies of annual audits from 1937 through 1984, as well as letters and memos concerning specific financial matters.
  - Annual Audits, 1937-1947 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Annual Audits, 1948-1958 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Annual Audits, 1959-1969 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Annual Audits, 1970-1984 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Finance Committee, 1920-1964, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - U.S. Department of the Treasury, 1938-1964 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Series V: Community Activities, 1930-1962
  Contains files on various organizations that the Four A's allied itself with or otherwise engaged. The material on the Federal Theater Project contains one letter from Hallie Flanagan. There is substantial material on the World's Fair and the contemporaneous San Francisco Exposition.
  Arranged chronologically within topics.
  - Theater Authority, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Theater Authority, 1941-1942, 1944, 1949-1951 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Theater Authority, 1953-1957, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Actors' Fund of America, 1940-1942, 1953, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - San Francisco Exposition, 1938-1940 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - World's Fair, 1937-1940 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - International Theater Convention, 1938-1939 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - National Theater, 1975, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Camp Shows, Inc., 1941-1942, 1948, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - ILO/UNESCO, 1956-1959 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - ILO/UNESCO, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Theater Arts Committee, 1930, 1938-1940 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - National Child Labor Committee, 1939-1941 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Federal Theater Project, 1938-1940 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - American Theater Council, 1937-1939 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - League of New York Theaters, 1938, 1941, 1949-1953 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - American Theater Wing, 1948-1951, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Series VI: Subjects, 1937-1993
  Includes files on the unsuccessful attempts to merge the various affiliates, the Committee on Integration of Negro in Theatre, and the Television Committee.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject, and chronologically within subjects.
  - American Federation of Musicians, 1938-1944, 1948, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Committee on Greek Actors, 1938-1943 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Committee on Models Federation of America, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Comm. on Integration of Negro in Theater, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Comm. on Integration of Negro in Theater, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Comm. on Integration of Negro in Theater, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Comm. on Integration of Negro in Theater, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Misc. Memos and Reports, 1939, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Merger-Petitions, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Merger, 1944-1948 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Merger, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Merger, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Merger, Jan-June 1952 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Merger, Aug-Dec 1952 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Merger, 1955-1993 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Television Committee, 1938-1940 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Television Committee, 1947-July 1949, 1947-1949 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Television Committee, Aug-Nov 1949 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Television Committee Minutes, Feb-Nov 1949 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Series VII: Affiliates, 1909-1993
  Comprises almost two-thirds of the processed materials, and is nearly equally divided between records of American Guild of Variety Artists (AGVA) affiliates, which principally concerns ongoing allegations and investigations of corrupt practices (1940s-1970s), and files pertaining to other affiliates, including smaller and/or more ephemeral groups such as the American Federation of Artists (Charter Revocation, 1939-42), the Burlesque Artists Association, Chorus Equity Association, Grand Opera Choral Alliance, Motion Picture Players/Screen Players Union, Screen Extras Guild, the Television Authority (1949-52), the White Rats Actors Union, and several ethnically-based affiliates, including the Hebrew Actors Union, Hungarian Actors and Artists Association, Italian Actors Union, Polish Actors Union, Puerto Rican Artists and Technicians Association, and the Yiddish Playwrights League.
  Arranged alphabetically by organization name.
  - Subseries: VII:A: General
    - American Artists Federation (AAF), 1919-1923, 1926, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Actor's Equity Association (AEA), 1919-1929 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - AEA, 1937-1938 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - AEA, 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - AEA, 1941-1949 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - AEA, 1950-1953 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - AEA, 1954-1964 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Actors Betterment/American Federation of Actors (AFA), 1933-1934 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - AFA, 1935-1938 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - AFA, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - AFA: Charter Revocation, Jan-May 1939 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - AFA: Charter Revocation, June 1939 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - AFA: Charter Revocation, July 1939, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - AFA: Charter Revocation; Legal Fees, 1939-1942 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - AFA: Charter Revocation; Trial Exhibits, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - AFA: Charter Revocation; Clipping File, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - American Federation of Radio Artists (AFRA), 1937-1939 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - AFRA, 1940-1944 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - AFRA, 1945-1952 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - AFTRA, 1952-1957 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - AFTRA, 1958-1965 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - American Guild of Musical Artists (AGMA), 1937-1947 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - AGMA, 1948-1964, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Burlesque Artists Association (BAA), 1933-1939 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - BAA, 1940-1957 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Chorus Equity Association, 1919-1940 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Chorus Equity Association, 1941-1955 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Grand Opera Choral Alliance, 1919-1923 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Grand Opera. Choral Alliance, 1924-1929, 1937-1939 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Grand Opera Artists Association, 1935-1941 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Hebrew Actors Union, 1919-1922 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Hebrew Actors Union, 1923-1929, 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Hebrew Actors Union, 1939-1953, 1958-1962 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Hebrew Chorus Union, Philadelphia, 1919-1933 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Hebrew Chorus Union, NY, 1919-1929, 1938-1940, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
      1945
    - Hungarian Actors and Artists Association, 1924-1942, 1946-1950 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Italian Actors' Union, 1937-1939 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Italian Actors' Union, 1940-1950, 1956, 1960-1961 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Motion Picture Players/Screen Players Union, 1919-1923 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Polish Actors' Union, 1919-1922 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Puerto Rican Artists and Technicians Association (APATE), 1961 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - APATE, Mar 1961-1974 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Screen Actors Guild (SAG), 1934-1938 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - SAG, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - SAG, 1941-1945 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - SAG, 1946-1948 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - SAG, 1949-1956 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - SAG, 1957-1965, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Screen Extras Guild (SEG), 1944-May 1945, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - SEG, Jun-Aug 1945 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - SEG, Sep-Dec 1945 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - SEG, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - SEG, 1947-1965, 1990, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Singers Guild of Los Angeles, 1930-1936 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Television Authority (TVA), Nov 1949-1950 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - TVA, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - TVA, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - TVA Minutes, Jan-Aug 1951 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - TVA Minutes, Sep 1951-Jan 1952, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - TVA -- Minutes, Feb-Sep 1952 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Yiddish Playwrights League, 1918-1925 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - White Rats Actors Union, 1909-1926 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - White Rats Actors Union, 1927-1939 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - White Rats Actors Union - History, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Subseries VII:B: American Guild of Variety Artists (AGVA)
    - AGVA, 1939-1940 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - AGVA, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - AGVA, Jan-Aug 1942 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - AGVA, Sep-Dec 1942 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - AGVA, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - AGVA, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - AGVA, 1946-1948 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - AGVA, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - AGVA, 1951-1957 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - AGVA, 1958-1962 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - AGVA, 1963-1969 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - AGVA, 1970-1976 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - AGVA: Four A's Committee on AGVA Elections, 1941-1942 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - AGVA: Financial Reports, 1942-1944 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - AGVA: Financial Reports, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - AGVA: Financial Reports, 1954, 1961, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - AGVA: Shelvey Ouster: Background and Evidence, 1939-1941 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - AGVA, Background and Evidence, 1942-1944 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - AGVA, Background and Evidence, 1945-1946 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - AGVA, Background and Evidence, Jan-Apr 1947 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - AGVA, Background and Evidence, May-Jun 1947 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - AGVA, Background and Evidence, Jul-Sep 1947 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - AGVA, Background and Evidence, Oct-Dec 1947 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - AGVA, Local Convention Nominations: Akron-Columbus, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - AGVA, Local Convention Nominations, Dallas-Montreal, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - AGVA, Local Convention Nominations, New Jersey-Youngstown, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - AGVA, Litigation Fees, 1948-1950 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - AGVA, Litigation Fees, 1951-1957 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - AGVA, Conference Proceedings, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - AGVA, Member Petitions, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - AGVA, Four A's Executive Committee, 1947-1948 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - AGVA, Background for Congressional Inquiry, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - AGVA, Clipping File, 1947-1948 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - AGVA, Continued Litigation, 1948-1951 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - AGVA: National Leadership Crisis: Background and Evidence, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - AGVA, Background and Evidence, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - AGVA, Background and Evidence, Jan-Jun 1972 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - AGVA, Background and Evidence, Jul-Dec 1972 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - AGVA, Background and Evidence, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - AGVA, Background and Evidence, Jan-Mar 1974 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - AGVA, Background and Evidence, April 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - AGVA, Member Correspondence, 1968-1971 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - AGVA, Member Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - AGVA, Roberts and Miller Reports, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - AGVA, Clipping File and Basic Agreements, 1968-1976 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - AGVA, VEGA Dispute, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - AGVA, Finance Memos, 1972-1974 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - AGVA, Alan Cory Litigation, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - AGVA, Penny Singleton Charges, 1959-1963 (Box 10, Folder 15)